

PINAKI DAS

Information



Address

Narayan Pally, Durganagar Kolkata - 700049 WB India



Phone

+91-9831404806



Email

pinakidas@outlook.in

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A multi-talented, solution-oriented, and highly analytical IT professional with a wide range of skills in systems installation, configuration, upgrading, and maintenance. Skillful administration and troubleshooting expertise for a range of Microsoft OS and Windows Server products.



SKILLS

- · Windows Server Remote Desktop
- VM-Ware Workstation
- Office365
- SCCM Client
- ServiceNow
- LINUX
- Windows 7/10
- Trend Micro & K7 AV
- · Active Directory
- Basic Networking

Social



LinkedIn

pinaki-dasb68303199

CERTIFICATIONS

- MCP Microsoft Certified Professional
- · MCSA Microsoft Certified System Administrator
- Oracle DBMS course from SQL Star

EXPERIENCE

03/2019 - 06/2020

Kolkata

CREATION

End User Lead

Project - Apollo Gleneagles Hospitals Ltd.

- Windows Server installation & configuration.
- Customization of RDP port on Server.
- Office 365 package, SCCM client, K7-AV installation & configuration.

 Providing remote support through SCCM Remote Console. Administration of K7-AV Console & patch upgradation on client systems. Windows patch update through SCCM Console. Incident & Change Management using ServiceNow ticketing tool. • Responsibility on the End-user IT technical support. Actively manage missing results with sites and internal teams in a timely manner. Manage escalations from Executives, providing full and regular updates while the issue in being investigated, and detailed explanations once the incident is resolved. Prioritize workload based on urgency and impact to customers and the business. Work closely with the training team and serve as SMEs to provide input and review training courses and participate in refresher training sessions. 07/2011 - 03/2019TECHNOSOFT SERVICES LTD. Kolkata Sr. Support Engineer Project - TATA STEEL LTD. · Lotus Notes 8 Client end installation, configuration & troubleshooting. • SAP 7 Client end installation, configuration & troubleshooting. · Outlook mail application installation, configuration & troubleshooting. • Trend Micro Office scan-AV endpoint Console monitoring & Threat report generation. Maintaining & managing Windows software, hardware, networking. Windows Server installation & configuration with RAID-1. • Domain joining, AD ID password reset.

05/2010 - 07/2011 Kolkata	1 INTARVO TECHNOLOGIES LTD. Support Executive
	Project - TMILL
	 Installation & configuration Microsoft® Products. Maintaining Windows Server Administration. Desktop, Laptop Hardware maintenance. Symantec-AV Console monitoring.
08/2006 - 05/2010 Kolkata	10 RT OUTSOURCING SERVICES LTD. Technical Support Engineer
	Project - TELCON
	 Installation & configuration Microsoft® Products. Outlook Configuration. AV Installation, configuration & updation. Hardware support on Laptops, Desktops. OS (Win XP/ Vista) installation & configuration. Installation & Configuration different MF-Printers.
10/2005 – 08/2006 Kolkata	O6 ACCEL-ICIM FRONTLINE LTD. Associate Engineer
	Project - USHA Comm.
	 Installation & configuration Microsoft® Products (Windows XP, MS-Office). Installation of utility applications, like - Adobe, Flash Player, Firefox browser, MacFee Antivirus client.



2012 – 2014 SIKKIM MANIPAL UNIVERSITY

MBA (IT)

2002 – 2005 VISVA-BHARATI UNIVERSITY

B.Sc (IT)

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

• Year -- Conduct by --- Training Topic

• 2020 -- AEM------RH-124, RHCSA Training on RHEL 8.0.

• 2019 -- HP-----ServiceNow Training.

• 2014 -- HP------HPSM Training.

• 2013 -- HP-----Trend-Micro OSCE Advance Training.

• 2009 -- HP------Windows Vista security δ profile Mgmt.

• 2008 -- HP------Windows Security, Firewall, User Account Mgmt.

• 2007 -- HP------AD Joining, Asset Mgmt, End-user Mgmt.

PERSONAL VITAE

• Date of Birth :04th July 1981

· Languages Known: English, Hindi, Bengali

· Passport Status: Available

DECLARATION

REFERENCES & DOCUMENTS AVAILABLE ON REQUEST